<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tools | My Web Adventures]]></title>
  <link href="http://AydinSakar.github.io/blog/categories/tools/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://AydinSakar.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-17T12:17:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://AydinSakar.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Aydın Sakar]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://AydinSakar.github.io/blog/2013/07/17/octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-17T11:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://AydinSakar.github.io/blog/2013/07/17/octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am using <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> to publish this blog.</p>

<p>I am using Windows 7 for daily work so had to install Octopress and GitHub on a Windows machine. I am planning to write a series of tutorials on the problems I faced making all work together with Windows.</p>

<p>I just want to make a brief note about the confusion I had when I tried to understand Octopress: The repository structure.</p>

<p>You have to have username.github.io named repository at <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a> to use GitHub Pages. The repository of this blog is: <a href="https://github.com/AydinSakar/aydinsakar.github.io">aydinsakar.github.io</a> You can also have project pages, but that is another topic for a blog post.</p>

<p>Octopress manages two branches in your username.github.io repository:</p>

<ol>
<li>master branch:
This is the actual branch that GitHub uses to publish your blog. When Github sees a push to this branch, they republish your content.</li>
<li>source branch:
This contains the source of Octopress <em>AND</em> your blog posts. Octopress generates the content from this branch and puts everything in a &ldquo;_deploy&rdquo; directory which is the actual &ldquo;master&rdquo; branch which is then pushed to GitHub. You have to remember to commit and push the &ldquo;source&rdquo; branch yourself.</li>
</ol>


<p>The bottom line is &ldquo;master&rdquo; is the generated blog, and the &ldquo;source&rdquo; is the raw stuff. They are not actually branches of a source tree in a usual sense. These two branches are completely different thigs which you should never manually deal with. This is kind of a <em>hack</em> that I had to understand, and which probably was the source of quite a bit of a confusion.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workflowy]]></title>
    <link href="http://AydinSakar.github.io/blog/2013/07/16/workflowy/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-16T08:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://AydinSakar.github.io/blog/2013/07/16/workflowy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Workflowy Rocks!</h2>

<p>I just learned about <a href="https://workflowy.com/?ref=14e3069c">Workflowy</a>. It is a super duper easy todo/note taking/organizing/cheat sheet/mind map/brain map/whatever tool.</p>

<p>Disclaimer: I earn 250 items/month if you follow this link and register to be a member.</p>

<p>It is free to use for 500 items/month and you get 250 items/month for each person using your link to register. Pro version is $4.99/month or $49/year, which is not that bad for this fantastic tool.</p>

<p>Give it a try!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
